Thanks for watching!
二零二五年山西省初中学业水平考试
英语听力测试。
一情景反应。
本题共有五个小题，每小题你将听到一组对话，请从每小题所给的
三幅图片中选出与你所听到的信息相关联的一项，并在答题卡。
1. Wow! The chair looks nice!
Thank you. My father made it for me.
2. I often water the plant for my grandma.
How helpful you are!
I often water the plant for my grandma.
3. The shoes are on sale.
I want to have a look.
Dear, I don't think you need any.
4. to music makes me feel relaxed.
Yes, it really works.
5. Jenny, what time is it now in your country?
It's ten in the evening.
Jenny, what time is it now in your country?
二，对话理解。
本题共有五个小题，每小题你将听到一组对话和一个问题，请从每小题所
给的
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项，并在答题卡。
将该项涂黑，读两遍。
Dialogue understanding
6. Amy, do you often eat vegetables to keep healthy?
Of course, and I sometimes drink juice, but I never eat fast food.
Question. How often does Amy eat vegetables?
Amy, do you often eat vegetables to keep healthy?
Of course, and I sometimes drink juice, but I never eat fast food.
Question. How often does Amy eat vegetables?
7. Cindy, you came to school earlier than me.
Yes, Bob. I'm on duty today, but David came much earlier.
Question. Who came to school earliest?
Cindy, you came to school earlier than me.
Yes, Bob. I'm on duty today, but David came much earlier.
Question. came to school earliest?
8. me, where can I find some books about history?
They are on the second bookcase on the left.
Question. Where are the two speakers?
Excuse me, where can I find some books about history?
They are on the second bookcase on the left.
Question. Where are the two speakers?
9. The moon is round tonight.
Let's admire the moon and share mooncakes.
Question. Which festival are they enjoying?
The moon is round tonight.
Let's admire the moon and share mooncakes.
Question. Which festival are they enjoying?
10. I feel bad.
I just play an unimportant role in a school show.
Come on, Jack.
Every role makes a difference.
Question. What does the girl mean?
I feel bad.
I just play an unimportant role in a school show.
Come on, Jack.
Every role makes a difference.
Question. What does the girl mean?
3. One night, Bill was lying in bed.
三与。偏理解。
本题你将听到一个语篇，请根据所听内容和所提出的五个问题，从每小题
所给的
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项，并在答题卡上将该项涂黑。
读两遍。
Then he heard his parents talking about his sister Anna's birthday two days away.
The family was too poor to buy any gifts.
Nearly all of the toys were made by mom.
Bill had seen Anna stopping at a toy bear in the gift shop window many times.
How he wished her to have it.
The next day, Bill went to the apple tree land.
He went past some friends playing soccer.
Join us, Bill, they called.
Sorry, guys, not today, he answered.
When he arrived, some people had already picked the big apples on the small trees.
There were many on the toilet trees, but he couldn't get them.
To solve the problem, Bill found a lawn stick to reach the high apples.
By late afternoon, he went to the gift shop with his bag full of big apples.
The following morning, put a basket of apples on the breakfast table.
Good morning, birthday girl.
My favorite fruit.
Thank you, Bill, said Anna.
She picked up the top apple.
Then she smiled brightly.
There, among the apples, was the new toy bear.
It was the brother's love that made the little girl stay.
One night, Bill was lying in bed.
Then he heard his parents talking about his sister Anna's birthday two days away.
The family was too poor to buy any gifts.
Nearly all of the toys were made by mom.
Bill had seen Anna stopping at a toy bear in the gift shop window many times.
How he wished her to have it.
The next day, Bill went to the apple tree land.
He went past some friends playing soccer.
Join us, Bill, they called.
Sorry, guys, not today, he answered.
When he arrived, some people had already picked the big apples on the small trees.
There were many on the toilet trees, but he couldn't get them.
To solve the problem, Bill found a lawn stick to reach the high apples.
By late afternoon, he went to the gift shop with his bag full of big apples.
The following morning, Bill put a basket of apples on the breakfast table.
Good morning, birthday girl.
My favorite fruit, thank you, Bill, said Anna.
She picked up the top apple.
Then she smiled brightly.
There, among the apples, was the new toy bear.
It was the brother's love that made the little girl stay.
4. Hello, everyone.
四，听力填空。
本题你将听到一个语篇，请根据所听内容完成下面的句子，并将获取的信
息写在答题卡相应的位置上。
每空一词，读两遍。
This is School English Broadcast.
We've got big news to share right here.
On May 12, the guidelines for general AI education in primary and secondary schools
came out. This guide will bring AI education to schools.
It asks primary schools to develop students' interest in AI and introduce basic
knowledge. They can use toys, cartoons, and stories to teach or explain with live
examples. Junior high schools should help students know how AI works and practice
enough to use it freely.
For example, they can ask students to make simple robots through projects.
As for senior high schools, they need to focus on training students to think about
things as a whole and encourage them to develop AI tools to help solve the problems
in real life.
The guide hopes that through AI education, students can get knowledge, skills,
thinking ability, and values that a smart society needs.
With these, students can build a bright future for themselves.
And with these, they will also play an important role in building a bright future
for our country.
Hello, everyone. This is School English Broadcast.
We've got big news to share right here.
On May 12, the guidelines for general AI education in primary and secondary schools
came out. This guide will bring AI education to schools.
It asks primary schools to develop students' interest in AI and introduce basic
knowledge. They can use toys, cartoons, and stories to teach or explain with live
examples. Junior high schools should help students know how AI works and practice
enough to use it freely.
For example, they can ask students to make simple robots through projects.
As for senior high schools, they need to focus on training students to think about
things as a whole and encourage them to develop AI tools to help solve the problems
in real life.
The guide hopes that through AI education, students can get knowledge, skills,
thinking ability, and values that a smart society needs.
With these, students can build a bright future for themselves.
And with these, they will also play an important role in building a bright future
for our country.
concludes
听力测试到此结束。